RG 004:137, Stonington Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Stonington Probate Court records
1708-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Stonington District)
53 cubic feet
Record books, 1767-1944; Probate files, 1708-1875, bulk 1766-1875; Wills, 1930-1976; Adoptions, 1881-1941.
RG004_137
1912-010, 2011-066, 2011-067
Historical Note
Stonington, New London, Town settled in 1649, named Souther Towne by Massachusetts, October 1658, Named Stonington by Connecticut in 1666, Stonington was claimed by both the Connecticut and Massachusetts Colonies. The location of the early probate records is doubtful, perhaps a part of these records will be found in Massachusetts, and part in the records of the Particular Court.
The Stonington Probate District was constituted October 1766, from the New London Probate District. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Groton, October 1766 - May 24, 1839; Ledyard, May 1836 - June 5, 1837; North Stonington, May 1807 - June 3, 1835. The Stonington Probate District merged with Groton, Ledyard, and North Stonington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Southeastern Corner Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Groton, Ledyard, North Stonington, and Stonington.
Town of Stonington, Probate District chronology:
1649 - 1662, Massachusetts Jurisdiction
1658 - May 1666, Particular Court Jurisdiction
May 1666 - October 1766, New London County Court & District
October 1766 - January 4, 2011, Stonington District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Southeastern Corner Regional District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-49. Two general indexes and 22 separate indexes for volumes 25-31, 33, 35-43, 45-49. Contact the probate court to access original record books. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1708-1875, bulk 1766-1875. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1708-1875 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Wills, 1930-1976.
Adoptions, 1881-1941
Arrangement
Record books in accessions 2011-066 are numnbered 1 to 49. The two general indexes are numbered 1 and 2. There are 22 separate indexes for volumes 25-31, 33, 35-43, 45-49.
Probate files in accession 1912-010 are arranged alphabetically. Wills in accession 2011-067 are arranged alphabetically. Adoptions in accession 2011-067 are arranged by docket number.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-010 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the wills and adoptions in accession 2011-067.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Groton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Ledyard; Probate records -- Connecticut -- North Stonington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Stonington
Places:
Groton (Conn.); Ledyard (Conn.); North Stonington (Conn.); Stonington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-066, Record books, 1767-1944, and accession 2011-067, Wills, 1930-1976, and Adoptions, 1881-1941, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-31, 35-37, 40-42, 1767-1933; probate files, 1766-1875 (Accession 1912-010); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-010 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): August 29, 1912 (1708-1875).
The record books in accession 2011-066 and the wills and adoptions in accession 2011-067 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 13, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1767-1944; 31.5 cubic feet (51 volumes + 22 indexes); 2011-066
  There are 2 volumes of general indexes and 22 separate indexes for volumes 25 through 49 except for the following volumes: 32, 34, 44
  - General index (Volume 1)
  - General index (Volume 2)
  - Journal and records, 1767-1772 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1772-1777 (Volume 2)
  - Journal and records, 1777-1781 (Volume 3)
  - Journal and records, 1781-1786 (Volume 4)
  - Journal and records, 1786-1795 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1795-1802 (Volume 6)
  - Journal and records, 1802-1809 (Volume 7)
  - Journal and records, 1809-1812 (Volume 8)
  - Journal and records, 1812-1815 (Volume 9)
  - Journal and records, 1815-1819 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1819-1825 (Volume 11)
  - Journal, 1819-1828 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1825-1830 (Volume 13)
  - Journal, 1828-1836 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1830-1837 (Volume 15)
  - Journal, 1836-1849 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1838-1845 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1845-1855 (Volume 18)
  - Journal, 1849-1858 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1855-1865 (Volume 20)
  - Journal, 1858-1869 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1864-1878 (Volume 22)
  - Journal, 1869-1877 (Volume 23)
  - Inventory, 1872-1886 (Volume 24)
  - Journal, 1878-1886, 1898 (Volume 25)
    Contains orders and decrees
  - Wills, 1877-1891 (Volume 26)
  - Journal, 1883-1888 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1883-1892 (Volume 28)
  - Journal, 1889-1895 (Volume 29)
  - Wills, 1890-1899 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1892-1898 (Volume 31)
  - Bonds, 1881-1896 (Volume 32)
  - Inventory, 1886-1900 (Volume 33)
  - Bonds, 1896-1913 (Volume 34)
  - Orders and decrees, 1894-1900 (Volume 35)
  - Wills, 1899-1911 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1898-1914 (Volume 37)
  - Accounts of administrators, executors, and trustees, 1900-1939 (Volume 38)
  - Inventory, 1900-1927 (Volume 39)
  - Orders and decrees, 1900-1905 (Volume 40)
  - Orders and decrees, 1905-1912, 1917 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1911-1933 (Volume 42)
  - Orders and decrees, 1911-1917 (Volume 43)
  - Bonds, 1913-1929 (Volume 44)
  - Orders and decrees, 1917-1923 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1914-1937 (Volume 46)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1923-1928 (Volume 47)
  - Inventory, 1927-1944 (Volume 48)
  - Orders and decrees, 1928-1932 (Volume 49)
- Probate files, 1708-1875, bulk 1766-1875; 18.5 cubic feet; 1912-010
  - Ackly - Bailey, D. (Drawer 1)
  - Bailey, E. - Brown, N. (Drawer 2)
  - Brown, O. - Chesebrough, M. (Drawer 3)
  - Chesebrough, N. - Danison, A. (Drawer 4)
  - Denison, B. - Ford (Drawer 5)
  - Foreseth - Henshaw (Drawer 6)
  - Heth - Lamb, D. (Drawer 7)
  - Lamb, E. - Minor, D. (Drawer 8)
  - Minor, E. - Oben (Drawer 9)
  - O'Connor - Perkins, L. (Drawer 10)
  - Perkins, M. - Phelps, Jon. (Drawer 11)
  - Phelps, Joseph - Prentice (Drawer 12)
  - Prince - Robbins (Drawer 13)
  - Robinson - Saunders (Drawer 14)
  - Sawyer - Shirley (Drawer 15)
  - Sholes - Smith, F. (Drawer 16)
  - Smith, G. - Smith, R. (Drawer 17)
  - Smith, S. - Stanton, D. (Drawer 18)
  - Stanton, E. - Stanton R. (Drawer 19)
  - Stanton S. - Starr (Drawer 20)
  - States - Sunehman (Drawer 21)
  - Swain - Targee (Drawer 22)
  - Taylor - Thurston (Drawer 23)
  - Tift - Vose (Drawer 24)
  - Waldo - Wells (Drawer 25)
  - Worden - Wheeler, H. (Drawer 26)
  - Wheeler, I. - Wheeler, R. (Drawer 27)
  - Wheeler, S. - Whiting (Drawer 28)
  - Whittlesey - Wilcox, I. (Drawer 29)
  - Wilcox, J. - Williams, B (Drawer 30)
  - Williams, C. - Williams, H. (Drawer 31)
  - Williams, I. - Williams M. (Drawer 32)
  - Williams, N. - Williams R. (Drawer 33)
  - Williams, S. - Woodbridge. C. (Drawer 34)
  - Woodbridge, D. - Wright (Drawer 35)
  - Yarrington - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 36)
- Inventory Control Book, 1708-1875; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1912-010
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate Files, 1881-1976; 3 cubic feet; 2011-067
  - Wills, Allen - Main, 1930-1976 (Box 1)
  - Wills, Mallette - York, 1930-1976 (Box 2)
  - Adoptions, Dockets 2-94, 1881-1941 (Box 2)